<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">

	<properties>
		<title>itracker Configuration</title>
	</properties>

	<body>
        <section name="Spring Context">
            <p>
                The Spring main application context is <code>/WEB-INF/classes/application-context.xml</code>
                which is optionally overridden by properties loaded in <code>/WEB-INF/classes/application.properties</code>.
            </p>
            <p>
                Since most configuration can be done from configuration properties (see below) and can be overridden by the JNDI bindings,
                usually there is no need to edit these files directly to configure the itracker application.
            </p>

        </section>

        <section name="JNDI Context">
            <p>
                Some JNDI environment resources are configured from the container running the itracker webapp.
                The lookup names are found in <code>application.properties</code>.
            </p>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    Configurable <code>configurationServiceTarget.jndiPropertiesOverridePrefix</code> from <code>WEB-INF/classes/application.properties</code>,
                    useful for overriding values in <code><a href="#Configuration_Properties">configuration.properties</a></code> from <code>java:comp/env/itracker</code>.<br/>
                    <em>eg. override <code>system_base_url</code> value with <code>java:comp/env/itracker/system_base_url</code> using the web.xml or context.xml.</em>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>Datasource</strong> (database connection):
                    <code>java:comp/env/itracker/itracker_ds</code> (see also <code>dataSource.jndiName</code> in application.properties and datasource.xml)
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>DB Dialect</strong> (hibernate dialect):
                    <code>java:comp/env/itracker/db_dialect</code> (see also <code>db_dialect.defaultObject</code> in application.properties and datasource.xml)
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>Mailsession</strong> (notifications, password, ..)):
                    <code>java:comp/env/itracker/mail/Session</code><br/>
                    <em>You can also override the lookup name by setting <code>configurationServiceTarget.mailSessionLookupName</code> but
                        usually you want to rather configure a mail-session accordingly for your web context.</em>
                </li>

            </ul>
        </section>

		<section name="Configuration Properties">
			<p>There are some properties which you're able to configure for your
			itracker (
			<code>classpath:configuration.properties
			</code>
			) or override the properties with env-entries under <code>java:comp/env/itracker/</code>
			</p>
			<ul>

				<li>
					<strong>system_base_url</strong>
					: This property can be used to override the url determined
					dynamically
					by the system when a user submits an issue or self registers. This
					is mainly due to some users using private domain names that wouldn't
					be accessible to all recipiants of a notification email. This
					property is only used to create urls in emails sent to all users.
					<br />
					<em>default: http://localhost:8080/itracker</em>

				</li>

				<li>
					<strong>web_session_timeout</strong>
					This property can be used to set the web session inactivity
					timeout. This number is the number of minutes that can elapse
					before the users
					session times out due to inactivity.
					<br />
					<em>default: 30 minutes</em>
				</li>

				<li>
					<strong>site_logo</strong>
					Set this if you wish to use an alternate image logo in the header
					of all
					pages. It must be a resolvable absolute path to the context-root. (type : String)
					<br />
					<em>default: shows no logo (null)</em>
				</li>
                <li>
                    <strong>site_title</strong>
                    Set this if you wish to use an alternate site title in the header
                    of all pages.
                    <br />
                    <em>default: itracker.org</em>
                </li>

				<li>
					<strong>available_locales</strong>
					Comma-separated list of available locales to the frontend.
					<br />
					<em>default: current default_locale from the configuration</em>
				</li>

				<li>
					<strong>default_locale</strong>
					Set to the default locale of the server. This controls the default
					language
					for users after they are logged in, and also the language of the login
					page before they are logged in. This HAVE TO be in the format
					language_country (eg. en_US, de_DE, pt_PT, it_IT) (type : String)
					<br />
					<em>default: en_US</em>
				</li>

				<li>
					<strong>create_super_user</strong>
					Set to true to create a default admin user if no other users exist
					in the
					database (type : Boolean)
					<br />
					<em>default: true</em>
				</li>

				<li>
					<strong>allow_forgot_password</strong>
					Set to true to allow users to recover their passwords (type :
					Boolean)
					<br />
					<em>default: true</em>
				</li>

				<li>
					<strong>allow_self_register</strong>
					Set to true to allow users to self register for your sever. This is
					a global
					setting that must be enabled for the project level options to be
					effective. If enabled, you must then go into each project you want
					accessible to self registered
					users, and which permissiosn you want. Currently only create and view all
					are
					available (view own is automatically granted), if you want other
					permissions, you
					must grant them using the normal user administration procedures. (type
					: Boolean)
					<br />
					<em>default: true</em>
				</li>

				<li>
					<strong>allow_save_login</strong>
					Set to true to allow users to save their login in a cookie on their
					machine
					for auto login. Setting this to false will not allow any user on the
					system
					to use this feature. (type : Boolean)
					<br />
					<em>default: true</em>
				</li>
				<li>
					<strong>save_login_key</strong>
					The "key" used to identify cookies from a specific token-based
					remember-me application.
					<br />
					<em>default: itracker</em>
				</li>
				<li>
					<strong>save_login_timeout</strong>
					The period (in seconds) for which the remember-me cookie should be valid.
					<em>default: 2592000 (30 days)</em>
				</li>

				<li>
					<strong>allow_workflowscripts</strong>
					Set to false to deny execution of workflowscripts for the system.
					Be sure that your system is protected against injection of
					malicious scripts when enabled. (type : Boolean)
					<br />
					<em>default: true</em>
				</li>

				<li>
					<strong>reminder_notification_days</strong>
					Defines the number of days after which issue reminder notifications will
					be sent.<br />
					Set to <code>0</code> to disable reminder notifications. (type : Integer)
					<br />
					<em>default: 30</em>
					<br />
					<em>
					To configure when reminders are sent, see application.properties reminder_cron.defaultObject
					</em>
				</li>

				<li>
					<strong>authenticator_class</strong>
                    This parameter sets the class to use for authentication.
                    The class must be resident in the classpath that the ear is loaded in,
                    and extend the org.itracker.services.authentication.PluggableAuthenticator
					abstract class. (type : String)
					<br />
					<em>default: Default-Authenticator</em>
				</li>

                <li>
                    <strong>max_attachment_size</strong>
                    The maximum size of an individual issue attachment in kb.
                    <br />
                    <em>default: 512</em>
                </li>

                <li>
                    <strong>max_total_attachment_size</strong>
                    The maximum total size of all attachments in kb.
                    <br />
                    <em>default: 100000</em>
                </li>

				<li>
					<strong>notification_from_address</strong>
                    <em>Deprecated: </em> From address for email notifications to use, if not set,
                    the mail-session default (mail.from) value will be used.
					<br />
					<em>default: mail.from as defined in mail-session</em>
				</li>

				<li>
					<strong>notification_from_text</strong>
					<em>Deprecated: </em> From address text for email notifications to use
					<br />
					<em>default: ITracker Notification System</em>
				</li>

				<li>
					<strong>notification_replyto_address
					</strong>
					<em>Deprecated: </em> ReplyTo address for email notifications to use, if not set,
					the notification_from_address value will be used.
					<br />
					<em>default: mail.from as defined in mail-session</em>
				</li>

				<li>
					<strong>notification_smtp_host</strong>
                    <em>Deprecated: </em> SMTP hostname for email notifications to use
					<br />
					<em>default: localhost</em>
				</li>

				<li>
					<strong>notification_smtp_charset</strong>
					<em>Deprecated: </em> SMTP notificate character set. You might need to change this for
					some locales
					<br />
					<em>default: the mail-session mail.mime.charset </em>
				</li>

				<li>
					<strong>notification_smtp_password and
						notification_smtp_userid</strong>
                    <em>Deprecated: </em> SMTP authentication userid and password if required by
					your application server
					<br />
                    <em>it is recommended to use a mail-session instead, only use this for fallback support. </em>
				</li>

                <li>
                    <strong>pdf.export.fonts</strong>
                    Fonts which will be included in exported PDFs, they are used from Jasper reports.
                    your application server
                    <br />
                    <em>Fonts are looked up in classpath: /fonts/#name#.ttf </em>
                </li>

			</ul>
		</section>
	</body>
</document>
